<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<node name="/Account_Manager_Interface_Creation" xmlns:tp="http://telepathy.freedesktop.org/wiki/DbusSpec#extensions-v0">
  <tp:copyright>Copyright (C) 2008 Nokia Corporation</tp:copyright>
  <tp:license xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
    <p>This library is free software; you can redistribute it and/or
modify it under the terms of the GNU Lesser General Public
License as published by the Free Software Foundation; either
version 2.1 of the License, or (at your option) any later version.</p>

<p>This library is distributed in the hope that it will be useful,
but WITHOUT ANY WARRANTY; without even the implied warranty of
MERCHANTABILITY or FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE.  See the GNU
Lesser General Public License for more details.</p>

<p>You should have received a copy of the GNU Lesser General Public
License along with this library; if not, write to the Free Software
Foundation, Inc., 51 Franklin Street, Fifth Floor, Boston, MA 02110-1301, USA.</p>
  </tp:license>
  <interface name="org.freedesktop.Telepathy.AccountManager.Interface.Creation.DRAFT">
    <tp:requires interface="org.freedesktop.Telepathy.AccountManager"/>
    <tp:docstring xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
      <p>The Creation interface provides methods and properties that are not
      yet finalized in the specs and that therefore are subject to change.</p>

    </tp:docstring>

    <method name="CreateAccount"
      tp:name-for-bindings="Create_Account">
      <tp:docstring xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
        <p>Request the creation of a new account, and sets the given properties on it.</p>

        <tp:rationale>
          <p>Besides for optimization reasons, it makes sense for some
          properties to be set as soon as the account is created (one being the
          "Profile" property in the Compat interface).</p>
        </tp:rationale>
      </tp:docstring>

      <arg name="Connection_Manager" direction="in" type="s"
        tp:type="Connection_Manager_Name">
        <tp:docstring>
          The name of the connection manager, e.g. "salut".
        </tp:docstring>
      </arg>

      <arg name="Protocol" direction="in" type="s"
        tp:type="Protocol">
        <tp:docstring>The protocol, e.g. "local-xmpp".</tp:docstring>
      </arg>

      <arg name="Display_Name" direction="in" type="s">
        <tp:docstring>The initial value of the new account's DisplayName
          property. The account manager MAY modify this to make it unique,
          for instance by appending a number or the 'account'
          parameter.</tp:docstring>
      </arg>

      <arg name="Parameters" direction="in" type="a{sv}">
        <tp:docstring>Initial parameter values, as would be passed to
          RequestConnection.</tp:docstring>
      </arg>

      <arg direction="in" name="Properties" type="a{sv}" tp:type="String_Variant_Map">
        <tp:docstring xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
          <p>The properties to be set, whose key must be in the form
          <code>Interface.PropertyName</code>.</p>
        </tp:docstring>
      </arg>

      <arg name="Account" direction="out" type="o">
        <tp:docstring>The new account.</tp:docstring>
      </arg>
    </method>

  </interface>
</node>
<!-- vim:set sw=2 sts=2 et ft=xml: -->
